catholic.net 2009-11-02

# Catholic.net - Catholics on the net

| 

Church Teaching Q&A

|   | 

Bible School  
  
---|---  
  | 

Canon Law  
  
  | 

Catholicism 101  
  
  | 

Church History  
  
  | 

Liturgy Explained  
  
Life & Family

|   | 

Chastity  
  
---|---  
  | 

Christian Men  
  
  | 

Christian Women  
  
  | 

Homosexuality  
  
  | 

Life & Bioethics  
  
  | 

Marriage  
  
  | 

Parenting  

Lifestyle

|   | 

Charity  
  
---|---  
  | 

Fitness  
  
  | 

Pilgrimages  
  
  | 

Relationships  
  
  | 

Singles  
  
  | 

Vocation  

Scriptures & More

|   | 

Bible  
  
---|---  
  | 

Catechism  
  
  | 

Code of Canon Law  
  
  | 

Papal Encyclicals  

Prayers & Devotions

|   | 

Devotionals  
  
---|---  
  | 

Faith  
  
  | 

Mariology  
  
  | 

Prayer Group  
  
  | 

Saints  
  
  | 

Traditional Prayers  
  
  | 

Testimonies  

News & Media

|   | 

Catholic.net Editor  
  
---|---  
  | 

Entertainment  
  
  | 

Events  
  
  | 

Media Watch  
  
  | 

News  
  
  | 

Newswire  
  
Faith & Finance

|   | 

Careers  
  
---|---  
  | 

Entrepreneurs  
  
  | 

Moral Investing  
  
  | 

Stewardship  

**Privacy Policy**

* * *

Catholic.net respects your right to the privacy of the personal information you provide us on our web site. Therefore, unless you specify otherwise or we state otherwise in this policy or at the time information is collected, any personal information you provide to Catholic.net will be not made known to any third party unless required to do so by court order, law or governmental agency. The following policy is intended to explain how your personal information will be treated as you make use of our sites and their features. Personal information includes your name and e-mail address, and click-through activity and any other personal information you may provide here. Changes in this policy will be posted in this section prior to implementation. Subscribers to our newsletter will also be alerted of any changes to this policy ahead of time. 

**Traffic data**

Every time a visitor comes to Catholic.net , our servers collect basic technical information, including, for example, the visitor´s domain (e.g. aol.com or ibm.com), referral data (e.g., we record the address of the last URL a user visited prior to Catholic.net) and browser and platform type (e.g., a Netscape browser on an IBM platform).

We also count, track and aggregate the visitor´s activity into our analysis of general traffic flows at our site (e.g. tracking where traffic comes from, how traffic flows within the Catholic.net site, etc. We will not disclose to any advertisers, or other third parties, your individual identity or personally identifiable data without your permission. When we do present aggregated information to outside companies, no one will be able to identify you or contact you.

**Use of Catholic.net cookies**

A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web server and stored on your computer´s hard drive. We may use cookies in a limited way to help deliver advertisements, to identify unique browsers that visit us and to track usage throughout our site. Other companies which place advertising on our site also have the ability to assign their cookies to you in a process that Catholic.net does not control. However, cookies cannot be used to identify individuals, only machines, so these advertisers will not know who

**E-mail newsletters**

Catholic.net sends an e-mail newsletter to subscribers who have requested it. The URLs (Web links) in these newsletters contain unique codes that allow Catholic.net to gauge the effectiveness of the newsletters and determine how they are being used. This information is valuable to us in the aggregate, but Catholic.net makes no use of it to track any individual user´s clicks.

**"E-mail to a friend" feature**

Catholic.net offers an "e-mail a friend about this story" feature, allowing site visitors to send e-mail to friends to inform them about an article they might be interested in reading. In order for this feature to function, we ask for e-mail addresses for the recipient (so we know who to mail the message to) and from the sender (so we can tell the recipient who sent the e-mail). No one will receive e-mail or other communications from Catholic.net or anyone else as a result of having used this feature.

"E-mail a friend about this story" is a mail service that individual visitors to Catholic.net make use of to send individual e-mails. While this tool cannot be used to send mass "spam" mailings, Catholic.net has no control over how our visitors use it, and any e-mail sent through it originates with, and is the responsibility of, the sender, not Catholic.net.

**Unsubscribe and data removal policies**

If you would like to unsubscribe from the Catholic.net newsletter please request removal of your e-mail address in the link below: [http://lists.catholic.net/remove/index.phtml?lista=Newsletter&mailss=newsletter-request@catholic.net ](http://lists.catholic.net/remove/index.phtml?lista=Newsletter&mailss=newsletter-request@catholic.net)

**Other sites**

Catholic.net contains many links to other sites on the Web. We cannot control and are not responsible for the privacy practices or content of these Web sites. 

**Who can I ask if I have any additional questions?**

If you have any further questions or concerns about Catholic.net´s privacy policies and use of personal information, please send them to contact@catholic.net. 

|  | 

Podcast & Webcast

|   | 

Daily Mass  
  
---|---  
  | 

Liturgy  
  
  | 

Radio  
  
  | 

Rosary  
  
  | 

Music  

Think & Learn

|   | 

Education  
  
---|---  
  | 

Environment  
  
  | 

Islam Facts  
  
  | 

Pope  
  
| Do you volunteer in your Parish?  
---  
Yes  
No  
Planning on it  

• See Results  
• Poll Archives  
  
Info & Resources

|   | 

Book Club  
  
---|---  
  | 

Catholic Directory  
  
  |
